paypaldeveloper.com 2012-05-16

# Privacy | X.commerce

**Jump to section:**

This policy describes the ways we collect, store, use and protect your personal information. You accept this policy when you sign up for or use our products, services or any other features, technologies or functionalities offered by us on our website or through any other means (collectively the “x.com Services"). This policy is effective the 3rd of October 2011.  We may amend this policy at any time by posting a revised version on our website. The revised version will be effective at the time we post it. In addition, if the revised version includes a substantial change, we will provide you with 30 days’ prior notice by posting notice of the change on the "Policy Updates" page of our website.

Our servers are located in the United States and elsewhere.  If you choose to provide us with personal information, you are consenting to the transfer and storage of that information on our servers in the United States and anywhere else we have facilities.

##  **Binding Corporate Rules**

In addition to the privacy practices set out in this Privacy Policy, eBay Inc. has established a set of Corporate Rules (also referred to as Binding Corporate Rules), approved by a number of European Union privacy regulators. These Corporate Rules are a commitment by eBay Inc. to adequately protect your personal information regardless of where the data resides, and depending upon your location, may provide additional privacy rights through your privacy regulator or a court. If you would like additional information regarding the Corporate Rules please visit, <http://www.ebayprivacycenter.com/binding-corporate-rules>.

##  **How we collect information about you**

When you visit the x.com website or use x.com Services, we collect information from and about your computer, including your IP address and standard web log information, such as your browser type and the pages you accessed on our website.

x.com is a subsidiary of eBay Inc.  If you open an account at x.com or are have an account with any other eBay Inc subsidiary, such as PayPal, Magento, or eBay,, we may collect additional information about you, such as:

  * Contact information - your name, address, phone, email, and other similar information.
  * Financial information - the full bank account numbers and/or credit card numbers that you link to your PayPal or other account or provide to us.
  * Community discussions, chats, dispute resolution, correspondence through our site, and correspondence sent to us.

Finally, we may collect additional information from or about you in other ways such as contacts with our customer support team, results when you respond to a survey, or  from interactions with members of the eBay Inc. corporate family, and from other companies.

##  **How we use cookies**

When you access our website, we, or companies we work with, may place small data files called "cookies" or image files called “web beacons” on your computer. We and our service providers also use these files to customize the x.com Services, content and advertising, measure promotional effectiveness, and improve the website experience.  

Most of these cookies are "session cookies" on your computer when you log in to your account or otherwise use the x.com Services. A session  cookie helps us to recognize you if you visit multiple pages on our site during the same session, so that we don’t need to ask you for your password on each page. Once you log out or close your browser, session cookies expire and no longer have any effect. 

We also use longer-lasting cookies for other purposes such as to display your logon in our sign-in form, so that you don't need to retype it each time you log in to your account. 

We encode our cookies so that only we can interpret the information stored in them. You are free to decline our cookies if your browser permits, but doing so may interfere with your use of our website.

You may encounter cookies from third parties when using the x.com Services on websites that we do not control (for example, if you view a web page created by a third party or use an application developed by a third party, there may be a cookie placed by that web page or application.)

##  **How we protect and store personal information**

Throughout this policy, we use the term "personal information" to describe information that can be associated with a specific person and can be used to identify that person. We do not consider personal information to include information that has been anonymized so that it does not identify a specific user. 

We store and process your personal information on our computers in the US and elsewhere in the world where eBay Inc. facilities are located, and we protect it by maintaining physical, electronic and procedural safeguards in compliance with applicable US federal and state regulations. We use computer safeguards such as firewalls and data encryption, we enforce physical access controls to our buildings and files, and we authorize access to personal information only for those employees who require it to fulfill their job responsibilities. 

##  **How we use the personal information we collect**

Our primary purpose in collecting personal information is to provide you with a secure, smooth, efficient, and customized experience. We may use your personal information to:

  * provide x.com Services and customer support you request;
  * process transactions and send notices about your transactions
  * resolve disputes, collect fees, and troubleshoot problems;
  * prevent potentially prohibited or illegal activities, and enforce our User Agreement;
  * customize, measure, and improve the x.com Services and the content and layout of our website and applications;
  * deliver targeted marketing, service update notices, and promotional offers based on your communication preferences;
  * compare information for accuracy and verify it with third parties.

##  **Marketing**

We don't sell or rent your personal information to third parties for their marketing purposes without your explicit consent. We may combine your information with information we collect from other companies and use it to improve and personalize the x.com Services, content and advertising. If you don't wish to receive marketing communications from us or participate in our ad-customization programs, simply indicate your preference by logging into your account and managing your preferences.

##  **Information shared with other Users on x.com**

Please note that your User ID may be displayed throughout x.com, especially when you make a comment or post.  This ID would then be available to the public.  User ID’s are connected to all of your x.com activity. Notices sent to other community members about suspicious activity and policy violations on our sites may refer to a User IDs.  Also note that if you access our sites from a shared computer or a computer in an internet café, certain information about you, such as your User ID or activity, may also be visible to other individuals who use the computer after you.

##  **How we share personal information with other parties**

We may share your personal information with:

  * Members of the eBay Inc. corporate family -- like eBay, PayPal, Magento, Shopping.com or Bill Me Later, Inc.-- to provide joint content, products and services (like registration, transactions and customer support), to help detect and prevent potentially illegal acts and violations of our policies, and to guide decisions about their products, services and communications. Members of our corporate family will use this information to send you marketing communications only if you have requested their services.
  * Service providers under contract who help with parts of our business operations such as fraud prevention, bill collection, marketing, and technology services. Our contracts dictate that these service providers only use your information in connection with the services they perform for us and not for their own benefit.
  * Credit bureaus to report account information, as permitted by law.
  * Companies that we plan to merge with or be acquired by. (Should such a combination occur, we will require that the new combined entity follow this privacy policy with respect to your personal information. If your personal information could be used contrary to this policy, you will receive prior notice.)
  * Law enforcement, government officials, or other third parties when
    * we are compelled to do so by a subpoena, court order or similar legal procedure
    * we need to do so to comply with law or credit card rules
    * we believe in good faith that the disclosure of personal information is necessary to prevent physical harm or financial loss, to report suspected illegal activity, or to investigate violations of our User Agreement.
  * Other third parties with your consent or direction to do so.

We will not sell or rent any of your personal information to third parties for their marketing purposes and only shares your personal information with third parties as described in this policy. 

##  **How you can access or change your personal information**

We delete personal information when we no longer need it for the purposes described above.  We retain personal information as permitted by law to resolve disputes and enforce our policies.  To access or correct your information, please contact us.

##  **How you can contact us about privacy questions**

For questions about this Policy email us via the x.com contact form or write to us at eBay Inc. Attn: Legal – Global Privacy Practices, 2145 Hamilton Avenue, San Jose, CA 95125.
